YOUSSEF HOURI



P: +1-226-260-0440





E: Youssef.houri@outlook.com A: https://www.linkedin.com/in /youssefhouri/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly dedicated Computer Science and Minor in IT graduate with a wealth of experience in full-stack development, from database design and API integration to user interface design and deployment. Adept at developing solutions in all working environments. Proven experience in developing web solutions for clients and consumer needs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Co-Founder/Developer

@ RedBirdDigital

JULY 2020 - PRESENT // WINDSOR, ON

- > Founded an agency that specializes in providing custom-made web design and development solutions to all industries.
- > Worked in a team of developers in delivering numerous complex projects based using the MERN Stack, Webflow, and WordPress to clients based in real estate, construction, food delivery, and more.
- > Showcased excellence in marketing, advertising, and client relations by doubling the client base for 3 consecutive months.

Undergraduate Teacher Assistant

@ University of Windsor

JAN 2022 - APR 2022 // WINDSOR, ON

- > Teacher assistant for Computer Concepts End-Users.
- > Performed all assistant teaching duties, including mentoring, grading assignments and tests, providing feedback and guidance, and regular data entry tasks on students grades.

EDUCATION

Computer Science & Minor in IT

@ University of Windsor

SEPTEMBER 2018 - DEC 2022 // WINDSOR, ON

Achieved a bachelor's degree in Computer Science and Minor in IT (Honours). Relevant Courses: Data Structures and algorithms, Web development, Mobile Application Development, World Wide Web Information Systems, Object Oriented Software Analysis and Design, and Agile Software Development.

SPECIALIZATIONS



Designing and developing beautiful websites backed by extensive knowledge in Full Stack Development.



Programming in **Python** to perform data analysis. Applied tools and technologies such as VBAs, Excel, Numpy, Pandas and Tensor.



Building long-lasting relationships and trusting connections with clients and coworkers.



PROJECTS

RedBirdDigital.co

Built a fully functional and responsive website made by using tools and technologies such as WordPress, HTML, CSS and JS. Serves as a business page for a co-founded web development agency.

Image Recognition Web App

A full stack web app made from scratch using HTML, CSS, JS, React, Node, Express and PostgreSQL. This web app is able to analyze a picture and determine the number of human faces within the pictures.

SKILLS

Languages

JavaScript, Python, Java, C, C++, HTML, CSS, Kotlin, SQL

Libraries & Frameworks

ReactJS, ExpressJS, NodeJS, MongoDB, Bootstrap, Flask, Git, Pandas and NumPy

Tools

WordPress, Webflow, Git, AdobeXD, Photoshop, and MS Suite